A Guide to the Frank Norris Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6905-a
Frank Norris Collection 1898-1952
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6905-a
21 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is opento research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1965 Nov 5
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Fragment from McTeague, [1899]; AMs, 1 p.
    [Begins "... evening papers, from somewhere in the building itself came a persistent note of sawing."]
  - Fragment from The Octopus, [1901]; AMs, 1 p.
    [Begins "closing the door behind her. The interior of the Mission.. "]
  - " The Great Corner in Hannibal and St. Jo ", AMs, 7 p.
    [Begins "In 1880 on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange certain brokers made popular the remark: 'When in doubt, sell Hannibal and St. Jo'."]
  - Inscription "To the Erie," a poem with a drawing of a train (in Blix [PS 2472.B5 1899b]), n.d.; AMS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Frank Norris to Lewis E[dwards] Gates, 1899 Feb 22; ALS, 2 p.
    (in
    McTeague
    [PS 2472.M3 1899 c2])
  - Frank Norris to Daniels, 1901 Dec 2; ALS, 2 p.
    [Gives requested advice on how to become a good reporter; says, in his opinion, the best school of journalism is the office of a journal.]
  - Frank Norris to Mr. and Mrs. Easton Ashe, ANS, 1 p.
    [Autograph inscription; remembers time spent in Santa Anita where
    The Octopus
    is set.] (in
    [PS 2472.O25 1901])
  - Jeannette Norris to John O'Hara Cosgrave, n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Asks to be sent Frank Norris' short stories.]
  - Robert L. Yard to John O'Hara Cosgrave, n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Returns a manuscript of Frank Norris' short stories, having decided not to publish them; hope and believes that Mrs. Norris will be able to make other arrangements for the book.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Check to Frank Norris from Albert B. Brady of the S. S. McClure Co., 1898 Dec 15; Check
    [Check for $12.00 endorsed by Norris.]
- Photographs
  - Frank Norris sitting in his study, working, by Frederic C. Clarke, for The World's Work, ante-1902; Photo
  - Pictures of Frank Norris in an exhibit at the Bancroft Library, University of California at Berkeley, ca. 1952; Photo
  - People looking at the Bancroft Library exhibit, 1952; Photo
  - People looking at the Bancroft Library exhibit, 1952; Photo
  - Display of some of Frank Norris' work, 1952; Photo
  - Display of books from Frank Norris' library, 1952; Photo
  - Display of books about Frank Norris, 1952; Photo
  - Display of Frank Norris manuscripts, 1952; Photo
  - Display of books by Frank Norris with inscriptions, 1952; Photo